- mnteristo94@gmail.c
- ★ 54 Av. Nicolas Pitiot, 69960 Corbas, France
- +19092749955

Languages

English

Skills

React

Ruby on Rails

Angular

Typescript

Vue

Tailwind CSS

Redux

HTML

CSS

Interests

Reading

Volleyball

Table Tennis

Alexandre Lee

Frontend developer

About me

Alexandre is an experienced full-stack web developer with almost a decade of experience working with a large variety of technologies—over half of that working remotely. He is equally comfortable collaborating with a team of developers. He has worked with satisfied clients.

Education

1 5.....

Bachelor's degree of Computer science

From April 2010 to October 2014 University of Lyon France

Work experience

Frontend developer

Since January 2020 Pricemoov United States

- Led the front-end development of a smart price recommendations platform used by large retail and eCommerce clients.
- Implemented and managed companies' Design System library.
- Profiled critical components, eliminating wasting renders which dramatically improved performance.
- Simplified the project structure, emphasizing reusability and scalability.

Technologies: React, TypeScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Redux

Frontend developer

From February 2019 to January 2020 Avatar Engines LLC United States

- Worked on providing API endpoints with Node.js/Inversify and MongoDB.
- Built from scratch admin platform for managing platform's database entities and users using React, Node.js, and Mongoose.
- Implemented complex UI components with React/TypeScript and SCSS.
- Improved the UX by creating several DnD-based components.
- Wrote scripts to use and manipulate data from various sources.

Technologies: MongoDB, Node.js, React, Redux, Typescript, Tailwind CSS

Frontend developer

From February 2018 to January 2019 Softimation United States

- Finished implementing a cryptocurrency exchange built using Angular.
- Handled the pixel-perfect implementation of the specs (Zeplin).
- Used Angular animations to improve the overall UX.
- Converted a web app to a native version using Cordova.
- Transformed the app to be mobile-first and fully responsive.

Technologies: NgRx, Angular, Typescript

Work experience

Frontend developer

From January 2017 to November 2018 Finam United States

- Rewrote and maintained a website's personal office. Refactored the legacy code and improved the codebase.
- Created HTML templates for a new website from Figma.
- Researched possible FE frameworks for the new website.
- Integrated a digital signature plugin with the website.

Technologies: JavaScript, Firebase, Pixel Perfect, Redux Form, MUI (Material UI), Redux Thunk, ECMAScript (ES6), CSS3 Animation, Responsive UI, Front-end Development, Adobe Photoshop, Figma, ASP.NET, Webpack, Gulp, Knockout (Knockout.js), Backbone.js, jQuery, PostCSS, Sass, Redux, React, User Interface (UI), Git, Immutable.js, CSS, React Router, Vanilla JS

Software Engineer

From January 2016 to January 2017 G-Global United States

- Designed and implemented a microservice architecture, allowing distributed GraphQL services with a cross-domain session for easy scale, faster development, and avoiding a single point of failure using Docker, Apollo, Express, Flask, and Jenkins.
- Oversaw the architecture and development of a real-time crossplatform desktop application that managed and optimized the daily operations of the transportation fleets with Electron and Socket.IO.
- Developed a mobile application to track drivers' routes, record times, and upload proof of delivery using React Native, Mapbox, and Twilio.
- Implemented several in-queue processing microservices for shipping order reception, invoice delivery, and PDF file compression using Python, Flask, and Celery.

Technologies: Docker, GraphQL, Express.js, , React Native, Python, Laravel, React, SendGrid

Frontend developer

From January 2015 to January 2017 Nafasi United States

- Created a live streaming product allowing video production companies to shoot remotely. Delivered collaboration tools, supported multi-camera shoots, and addressed latency challenges using multiple streaming protocols.
- Designed and implemented an industry-specific product for digitally signing, storing, and managing contracts for video production companies. Supported both web browser and iOS clients using an internal API using JSON:API specification.
- Built an Al-powered tool for detecting and confirming the presence of faces and other data in a piece of video footage.
- Used this data to dynamically generate Excel reports used by the industry for compliance and reporting.
- Managed a team of internationally-located freelance developers.
 Responsible for code reviews, feature scoping, and project management.

Technologies: Amazon Web Services (AWS), Heroku, Bootstrap, Capybara, RSpec, Ruby on Rails (RoR)